<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Portfolio</title><link>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on My Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/about/</guid><description>About me I enjoy connecting the dots: be it ideas from different disciplines, people from different teams, or applications from different industries. Having said that, I am a programming enthusiast with the motivation to analyze technical problems and provide effective software solutions. My engagement with various industries including Financial Business, Telecommunications, and Technology Leaders through internships and full time association have inculcated their values and culture in me that always motivates me to learn and grow.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/education/</guid><description>University of Texas at Dallas Masters in Computer Science (August 2019 - July 2021) Coursework Accomplished : Design and Analysis of Algorithm, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Artificial Intelligence, Database Design, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Web Programming Languages, Operating Systems Concepts, Discrete Mathematics
Vishwakarma Institute of Technology, Pune B.Tech in Electronics Engineering (July 2013 - May 2017) Coursework Accomplished : DataStructures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Organization, Computer Programming, Computer Networks, Computer Vision, Digital Image Processing, Microcontroller programming, Digital Circuits, Degital Electronics and Logic Design</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/experience/</guid><description>Software Development Intern – Security | Nokia | San Jose, CA Jan 2021 – Present • Working on a security product built on top of open-source project ‘Key Cloak’ to secure web based microservices. • Developed harmonized alarms logging feature to report database connectivity issues in the product logs.
Software Cloud Engineer Co-Op | WEX Inc | Portland, ME September 2020 – December 2020 • Designed and developed lightweight, Restful API to provide access to an existing application using spring boot.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Breast Cancer Diagnosis using KNN and SVM Fall 2020 • Performed nonlinear binary classification on breast cancer dataset using SVM with Radial Basis kernel and K nearest neighbour algorithm. Predicted possibility of being diagnosed with breast cancer for given test data. • Reduced the training error using hyperparameter tunning and regularization techniques.
Web Application for Real Estate Management: Spring 2020 • Developed a web application for managing properties using Angular8 as frontend, NodeJS, MongoDB as backend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/skills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/skills/</guid><description>Programming Exposure:
C, Core Java, Python, Shell Web Technologies:
HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, REST, SOAP, XML, JSON Databases:
MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB Machine Learning Libraries:
NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, NLTK Container Platforms:
Docker, Kubernetes, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, Redhat OpenShift AWS Platform Services:
EC2, VPC, ECS, ECR, EKS, IAM, Route 53, S3, Lambda, CloudFormation, CloudWatch Software Tools and Packages:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/testimonials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rupeshbiradar40.github.io/testimonials/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>